http://www.writerstrust.com/privacy

Skip to contentAboutBoard of DirectorsAuthors' Advisory GroupAwardsHilary Weston Writers’ Trust Prize for NonfictionWriters' Trust Fiction PrizeShaughnessy Cohen Prize for Political WritingMatt Cohen Award: In Celebration of a Writing LifeLatner Writers’ Trust Poetry PrizeVicky Metcalf Award for Literature for Young PeopleWriters’ Trust Engel Findley AwardRBC Bronwen Wallace Award for Emerging WritersWriters’ Trust McClelland & Stewart Journey PrizeDayne Ogilvie Prize for LGBTQ Emerging WritersProgramsCanadian Writers’ Emergency Relief FundWoodcock Fund GrantWriters' Trust FellowshipBerton House Writers' RetreatWriters' Trust Rising StarsWriters’ Trust MentorshipEventsPolitics and the PenWriters' Trust GalaWriters' Trust AwardsMargaret Laurence Lecture SeriesWriters & BooksAuthorsBooksAward HistoryProgram HistoryReading ListsSupportWays to ContributeOur SupportersStaff ContactFAQOur Privacy PolicyThe Writers’ Trust of Canada is committed to protecting the privacy and personal information of its award and program recipients, employees, volunteers, members, directors, donors, and other stakeholders. We value the trust of those we deal with, and of the public, and recognize that maintaining this trust requires that we be transparent and accountable in how we treat the information that you choose to share with us.In support of our work encouraging a national writing community, the Writers’ Trust gathers and uses personal information during the course of our various projects and activities. Anyone from whom we collect such information should expect that it will be carefully protected; any use of this information is subject to consent in accordance with PIPEDA and provincial legislation in Alberta, British Columbia, and Quebec. Writers’ Trust privacy practices are designed to achieve this.Defining Personally Identifibale InformationPersonally Identifiable Information is any information that can be used to distinguish, identify, or contact a specific individual. This information can include an individual's opinions or beliefs, as well as facts about, or related to, the individual. Exceptions: business contact information and certain publicly available information, such as emails, addresses, and telephone numbers as published online and in telephone directories, are not considered Personally Identifiable Information.Information in the public domain is not subject to privacy legislation and as such is not included in this policy. If clients use their home contact information as business contact information, the Writers’ Trust considers that the contact information provided is business contact information, and is not therefore subject to protection as Personally Identifiable Information. We never disclose details about donors, volunteers, or writers without consent.The Writers’ Trust observes the following practices when collecting, maintaining, and using personal information:ConsentAn individual’s consent is required regarding the collection and use of Personally Identifiable Information. Consent can be either express or implied and can be provided directly by the individual or by an authorized representative. Express consent can be given orally, electronically, or in writing. Implied consent is consent that can reasonably be inferred from an individual’s action or inaction. An individual’s express consent is required before confidential information is released to outside parties.CookiesThe Writers’ Trust uses cookies within visiting browsers to enable the functions of the website and for tracking performance. Cookies are also used in conjunction with third party services to measure web analytics with Google Analytics tools, conversion tracking such as with Facebook and Twitter ads, and click sources using MailChimp and Bitly.Cookies are used anonymously and without storing Personally Identifiable Information. Visitors that wish to opt-out of cookies should review the help documentation for their browser software to decline or selectively decline cookies. Note that declining cookies may adversely impact site performance.Review the help documentationGoogle AnalyticsThe Writers’ Trust website uses Google Analytics to track page performance, which uses persistent cookies to track visitor sessions, visitors across multiple sessions, and referral sources. We also track the performance of promotional links to our site. We use this data to understand site performance to serve you better. In compliance with Google’s Terms of Service, at no time is Personally Identifiable Information passed to Google Analytics. Note that Google stores its data within the United States of America and is subject to US laws. Those wishing to opt out of Google Analytics data collection should use this Opt-out Browser Add-on.TwitterThe Writers’ Trust website works with Twitter to collect user data for purposes of conversion tracking and serving ads targeted to users’ interests, for example to find users who like reading, or to target tweeters located in Canada. Anyone wishing to opt out of interest-based advertising should enable their browser’s Do Not Track (DNT) setting and also adjust their Twitter privacy settings.Twitter prohibits the creation of tailored audiences or conversion events based on any sensitive information, which includes: alleged or actual commission of a crime, health, negative financial status or condition, political affiliation or beliefs, racial or ethnic origin, religious or philosophical affiliation or beliefs, sex life, or trade union membership.The Writers’ Trust does not create advertisements which assert or imply knowledge of personally identifiable or sensitive information, even when the ad has been created and targeted without using such information.The Writers’ Trust does not use these products in any website, application, or service directed to children under the age of 13, or in any website, application, or service that collects or stores age information from individuals under the age of 13.The Writers’ Trust does not use these products in any case where the product, message, or service that the advertiser offers is otherwise prohibited by Twitter’s Ads Policies.Limited CollectionThe collection of Personally Identifiable Information is limited to that which is relevant and necessary to our literary program and fundraising efforts. The Writers’ Trust shall not make unwarranted or intrusive inquiries into a donor or prospect’s gift history or personal life. The Writers’ Trust attributes all data that it collects.Limited Use, Disclosure, and RetentionPersonally Identifiable Information shall not be used or disclosed for purposes other than those for which it was collected, except with the express consent of the individual or as required by law. Personally Identifiable Information shall be retained only as long as necessary for the fulfillment of those purposes.AccuracyPersonally Identifiable Information shall be as complete, accurate, and up-to-date as possible. Donors are encouraged to review, correct, and update their records.Security SafeguardsPersonally Identifiable Information gathered by the Writers’ Trust is kept in confidence and stored in a password protected database. Writers’ Trust personnel shall be authorized to access the information based only on need for the reason(s) for which it was obtained.Appropriate physical and electronic measures shall be used to ensure Personally Identifiable Information is secure. Access to donor and volunteer records shall be limited to those who require such information to fulfill their job responsibilities. Special protection shall be given to all records pertaining to anonymous donors. The confidentiality of donor and volunteer records shall continue after the relationship with the individual has ended.ConfidentialityDonors who request that their name or the amount of their gift not be publicly released shall remain anonymous.OpennessUpon request, individuals shall be given access to the information in their donor record. To make a request, please call 416 504-8222 x246 or email kafonso [@]writerstrust.comFurther information on privacy and rights in regard to personal information may be found on the website of the Privacy Commissioner of Canada at www.priv.gc.ca.AboutBoard of DirectorsAuthors' Advisory GroupAwardsHilary Weston Writers’ Trust Prize for NonfictionWriters' Trust Fiction PrizeShaughnessy Cohen Prize for Political WritingMatt Cohen Award: In Celebration of a Writing LifeLatner Writers’ Trust Poetry PrizeVicky Metcalf Award for Literature for Young PeopleWriters’ Trust Engel Findley AwardRBC Bronwen Wallace Award for Emerging WritersWriters’ Trust McClelland & Stewart Journey PrizeDayne Ogilvie Prize for LGBTQ Emerging WritersProgramsCanadian Writers’ Emergency Relief FundWoodcock Fund GrantWriters' Trust FellowshipBerton House Writers' RetreatWriters' Trust Rising StarsWriters’ Trust MentorshipEventsPolitics and the PenWriters' Trust GalaWriters' Trust AwardsMargaret Laurence Lecture SeriesWriters & BooksAuthorsBooksAward HistoryProgram HistoryReading ListsSupportWays to ContributeOur SupportersStaff ContactFAQPrivacy PolicyAnti-Harassment PolicyStay ConnectedE-NewsletterFacebookTwitterInstagramHomeWriters' Trust of Canada
